They’re going out with a bang.
Ice Age: Collision Course is a adventure, animation,
family film directed by Mike Thurmeier.
Set after the events of Continental Drift, Scrat's epic pursuit of his elusive acorn catapults him outside of
Earth, where he accidentally sets off a series of cosmic events that transform and threaten the planet.
To save themselves from peril, Manny, Sid, Diego, and the rest of the herd leave their home and embark on a quest full of
thrills and spills, highs and lows, laughter and adventure while traveling to exotic new lands and locations.
Manny (voice), played by Ray Romano.
Sid (voice), played by John Leguizamo.
Diego (voice), played by Denis Leary.
Ellie (voice), played by Queen Latifah.
Crash (voice), played by Seann William Scott.
Eddie (voice), played by Josh Peck.
Ice Age: Collision Course is a 2016 American animated
science-fiction comedy film produced by Blue Sky Studios.
The fifth in the Ice Age film series, it was directed by Michael Thurmeier,
and written by Michael Wilson, Michael Berg, and Yoni Brenner.
Ray Romano, John Leguizamo, Denis Leary, Josh Peck, Simon Pegg, Seann William Scott,
Jennifer Lopez and Queen Latifah reprise their roles from the previous films.
In the film, Scrat is propelled into outer space in an abandoned spaceship during an
attempt to bury his acorn and accidentally sends a giant asteroid towards Earth.
Manny, the Herd and Buck must go on a life-or-death
mission to find a way to fend it off.
The film premiered at the Sydney Film Festival on June 19, 2016, and was
theatrically released in the United States on July 22 by 20th Century Fox.
The film received generally negative reviews from critics and grossed
$408 million against a $105 million production budget.
While the film was deemed a disappointment at the American
box-office, it performed better internationally.
A spin-off film, The Ice Age Adventures of Buck Wild, was released in 2022, while a
further sequel, Ice Age: Boiling Point, is scheduled to be released in 2027.
The film explores themes of fire, fireworks, mammoth, sequel, prehistory.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.